### Erick Wendel Gomes da Silva

https://erickwendel.com

contato@erickwendel.com.br

São Paulo - Brazil

### **Profile**

Erick Wendel is a Speaker, Software Consultant and community Co-organiser in Brazil. Named by Microsoft as Most Valuable Professional, and by Google as Google Developer Expert, a specialist in Node.js and Javascript Applications. He is an Independent Solutions Architect who helps companies to make better and cheaper applications using Serverless architectures, Container based applications, and Hybrid Cloud solutions. He has experience speaking and teaching at the biggest conferences in Brazil and the Americas, working as voluntary Leader of NodeBR, Javascript São Paulo and Nerdzão Communities. http://erickwendel.com

# Experience

INDEPENDENT SOLUTIONS ARCHITECT AND TRAINER, EW.IT - 04/2018-PRESENT

Working as a Solutions Architect, writing architecture documents advising companies based on top technologies such as Kubernetes, Serverless applications (AWS and Azure) and Node.js. Teaching about how they would create scalable applications based on their resources. Training supplier for Microsoft, Gama Academy, Kroton Educacional and Opah IT Consulting teaching about Node.js, Javascript, Docker, Kubernetes and cloud computing related technologies.

Customers: <u>013 Innovation Space</u>, <u>Gama Academy</u>, <u>GS1 Brasil</u>, <u>JLCP</u>, <u>Kroton Educacional</u>, <u>Microsoft Brasil</u>, <u>Opah IT Consulting</u>, <u>Resolv Risk</u>.

Online training projects: <u>Kubernetes Marathon</u>, <u>Mastering in node.js training</u>, <u>First steps using Typescript on VSCode</u>.

LEAD SOFTWARE ARCHITECT, BEETECH GLOBAL - 06/2019-01/2020

Beetech is a company that does financial product. As a software architect I have worked on remessaonline.com.br product. My job was to find performance problems on Web APIs/Routines/etc and design new Microservices. I helped developers to create and prevent problems on Node.js applications based.

#### PARTNER AND CHIEF TECHNOLOGY OFFICER, HORIZON FOUR: 05/2017 - 05/2018

Horizon four was a consultancy company focused on digital transformation and innovation. I worked as a technology director, making decisions about tools, possible customers and projects. I was responsible to create and teach new development teams. We decided to split our paths, my ex-partners are focused on a product called by Shawee and I decided to continue as an independent consultant.

Principal Technologies: Node.js, Python, Javascript, GraphQL, C#, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, AWS, Microsoft Azure, Serverless applications, Linux based servers, Kubernetes, Docker and Ionic Framework.

**SENIOR SOFTWARE CONSULTANT, FCAMARA CONSULTING & TRAINING – 09/2016 - 05/2017**I worked as a senior software consultant focused on Node.js and Javascript applications. Our team was called by high-performance and critical operations, responsible to deliver projects with high technical complexity, the company most valuable team.

Principal Technologies: Node.js, Javascript, Python, MongoDB, Angular 1.x, Digital Ocean, Docker, Linux based servers.

### FULL STACK DEVELOPER, WATERMELON AGENCY BRAZIL - 05/2015 - 11/2015

Il was responsible to create, manage and release Python and Javascript tools to support the Renda Fixa app. In this startup, we had only two developers including me. I supported all end-to-end app ecosystem. I created automated robots to extract information from financial Brazilian websites. I build Restful APIs using Flask and Python. Hybrid applications using Ionic Framework 1.0 and native apps using Windows Phone 8.1 and Facebook canvas app.

Principal Technologies: Python, Javascript, Node.js, Ionic Framework, OpenShift, MongoDB, Selenium Web Driver, Linux based servers.

FULL STACK DEVELOPER, METHOD UNIVERSITY OF SÃO PAULO (FAMESP) – 11/2014 - 05/2015 I was responsible to create the new platform to support students, teachers, and employees. We had migrated legacy applications to the cloud.

Principal Technologies: C#, ASP.NET MVC 5,HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, SQL Server.

### WEB DEVELOPER, SSI CONSULTING - 07/2014 - 11/2014

I was responsible to develop platforms to support retired police government benefits (SPPREV), providing aggregation of documents and government workflow.

Principal Technologies: C#, ASP.NET Web Forms 4.0, SQL Server.

## Education

Faculdade Impacta Tecnologia (FIT), São Paulo Brazil – Software analysis and development, Graduated, 01/2014 - 06/2016.

## Licenses & Certifications

- MCPS: Microsoft Certified Professional Specialist Issued in 11/2015
- Microsoft Specialist: Programming in HTML5 with JavaScript and CSS3 Issued in 11/2015
- JSNAD: OpenJS Node.js Application Developer Issued in 01/2020

### Honors & Awards

One of the first fifty OpenJS Node.js Application Developers certified in the world - 01/2020

DeveloperWeek SF 2019 Hackathon Best Use of Clarifai Winner - 02/2019 - Clarifai

Google Developer Expert - Web Technologies - 01/2019 - Google

Most Valuable Professional in Web Technologies - MVP - 11/2018 - Microsoft

Master in Git - 7Masters - 11/2017 - iMasters

<u>AngelHack Global Hackathon Series: São Paulo 1st place winner</u> - 07/2017 - Angel Hack

Most Valuable Professional in Web Technologies - MVP - 02/2017 - Microsoft

Microsoft Student Partner - MSP - 07/2015 - Microsoft

# References

Twitter: @erickwendel\_

• Linkedin: <u>br.linkedin.com/in/erickwendel</u>

Github: github.com/erickwendel

Facebook: <u>fb.com/page.erickwendel</u>

• Website: erickwendel.com